Inventory to the J. C. Hurewitz papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Palestine
  - Histadruth (General Federation of Jewish Labour in Palestine)
    - Bulletins, 1948 (Box-folder 13: 16)
      In Hebrew. 4 items (processed).
    - Publications, 1943, 1945 (Box-folder 13: 17)
      Histadruth: General Federation of Jewish Labour in Palestine: Facts and Figures, 1945; Abba Khoushi, The Palestine Labour League, 1943 May.
    - "Labor in Palestine: The Labor Movement,", undated (Box-folder 13: 18)
    - "A Survey of Arab Labour Organisation in Palestine,", 1945 January (Box-folder 13: 19)
  - Institute of Arab American Affairs, New York
    - Bulletins, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 13: 20)
      40 items (processed).
    - Circulars, 1948 (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - Hitti, Philip K., "The Arab Claim to Palestine,", 1945 March 13 (Box-folder 13: 22)
    - Monthly progress report, 1946 January (Box-folder 13: 23)
    - Publications, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box-folder 13: 24)
      Constitution of the Institute of Arab American Affairs, 1945; Manifesto of the Institute of Arab American Affairs on Palestine, 1945 April; Memorandum of the Institute of Arab American Affairs on The Recommendations of the Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry, 1946 August; Kermit Roosevelt, Partition of Palestine: A Lesson in Pressure Politics, 1948 February; A. L. Warnshuis, Christians and Zionism, 1945 December.
    - Wadsworth, Ambassador George, address to the Institute, 1946 November 29 (Box-folder 13: 25)
  - Arab Office, Washington, D.C.
    - "The Arab Office,", undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Bulletins, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Publications, 1946-1947, undated (Box-folder 14: 3)
      The Arab World and the Arab League, undated; The First and the Last, 1946; W. T. Stace, The Zionist Illusion, 1947 February.
  - Jewish Agency for Palestine
    - Digest of Press and Events prepared by the Information Section, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 14: 4)
      9 items (partially processed).
    - Epstein, Eliahu, "The Lebanon,", 1943 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Extracts from the Arab Press in the U.S.A., 1946 (Box-folder 14: 6)
      11 items.
    - Joseph, Dr. Bernard, excerpted address at National Board Meeting, 1941 January 28 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Material in Hebrew and English, including excerpts from the Arab press, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 14: 8)
      23 items (partially processed).
    - Ussishkin, M., "To the Jews and the Zionists Throughout the World,", undated (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - League for Jewish-Arab Rapprochement. Circulars, 1942 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Nation Associates, New York. Memoranda submitted to the United Nations General Assembly, 1947 (Box-folder 14: 11)
- Turkey. 19 pamphlets, for the main part issued by the Turkish Information Office, relating to Turkish society, culture, economy, politics, and foreign policy, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 14: 12)
- United States. Hurewitz, J. C., "Undergraduate Instruction on the Middle East in American Colleges and Universities,", 1962 May 1 (Box-folder 14: 13)
- Guidebooks and souvenir albums, 1942-1960
  - Middle East, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 15: 1-6)
  - Soviet Union, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 15: 7-17)
  - Pakistan, 1960 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - India, 1960 (Box-folder 15: 19)
- Iran. Report on natural resources of the Khuzestan Region, 1959 (Box-folder 15: 20)
- Palestine, 1917-1948
  - Memoranda and reports, 1936-1948
    - 1936-1944 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 16: 3-5)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 16: 6-8)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1917-1947
    - 1917-1940 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - 1941-1944 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - 1945-1947 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Serial issues, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - United Nations Palestine Commission, 1948
    - Summary record, 1948 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Supplementary documents, 1948 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- British Information Services reports, 1947 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Soviet and East European Research Centre bulletins, 1976-1979
  - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Memoirs of Calouse Sarkis Gulbenkian, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Daily Digest of the Arabic Press, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Standard Oil Company report on Bahrein and Saudi Arabia, 1940 (Box-folder 18: 7)
- Treaties and agreements between Egypt and Syria relating to the United Arab Republic, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
- Official reports relating to the foreign policy of Saudi Arabia, 1955 (Box-folder 20: 1-3)
- United Nations Security Council working paper on the Palestine question, 1951 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
- Suez Canal Company survey, 1957 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Note on Arab unity by Nuri as-Sa'id, 1943 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Turkey, 1973-1980
  - Foreign Policy (Turkish serial issue), 1973-1980
    - 1973 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 22: 2-3)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Foreign policy reports published by the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1976-1977
    - 1976 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 22: 8-9)
- Conference papers on social welfare in Iran, 1982 (Box-folder 22: 10)
- Subject file, 1917-1950
  - Advertisements, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Amīn al-Husainī, Grand Mufti, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Anglo-American Commission of Inquiry, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Arab League, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - Arabian peninsula, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - Communists, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Economic and Social Council, 1946 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Egypt, 1938-1950 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Government papers, 1947 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Great Britain, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Iraq, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Land schemes, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Lebanon and Syria, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Mandatory policy, 1917-1947 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - North Africa, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Palestine, partition of, 1938-1947 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Palestinian Arab politics, 1938-1945 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Sephardic community, 1945 (Box-folder 24: 10)
  - Treaties and executive agreements, 1921-1946 (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - United Nations, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 24: 12)
  - Zionism, 1941-1947
    - Great Britain, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Religious, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Rightwing, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - United States, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- Academic career file, 1951-1978
  - American Jewish Year Book, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Committee on instruction, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Conference guidelines, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - General correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Government training project, 1951 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Istanbul conference, 1963 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Lebanon conference, 1963 (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Report and correspondence relating to trip to Middle East, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Reports on Israel by Ann and Jack Lesch, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Robert G. A. Jackson oral history transcript, 1978 (Box-folder 26: 2-3)
  - Student paper on Jerusalem, 1975 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Translations of treaties and decrees relating to the Russian Empire, 1964 (Box-folder 26: 5-7)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, the Middle East, and North Africa, 1922-1998
  - Monographs, 1938-1947 (Box-folder 27: 1-2)
  - Pamphlets, 1922-1981
    - General, 1922-1981 (Box-folder 27: 3-37)
    - Speeches by Abba Eban, 1949-1967 (Box-folder 27: 38)
  - Serial issues, 1946-1998
    - Palestine Affairs, 1946-1949
      - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 27: 39)
      - 1947-1949 (Box-folder 27: 40)
    - Middle Eastern Affairs, 1950-1962
      - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 28: 1-53)
      - 1954-1958 (Box-folder 29: 1-42)
      - 1954-1958 (Box-folder 30: 1-49)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Academic career file, 1976-1990
  - Correspondence, 1951-1989
    - General, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - General, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Papers and reports by others, listed by subject, 1976-1990
    - Arab-Israeli dispute, 1976 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - United States and the Middle East, 1978 (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - Krymchaks, 1989 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Temple Mount incident, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Subject file, 1898-1973
  - Anglo-American Committee of Inquiry, 1946 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Goldman, Nahum, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Jews in Egypt, 1949 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Nolte, Richard H., 1952-1953 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Palestine (British mandate), 1939-1945
    - General, 1939 (Box-folder 32: 2)
    - Political parties, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - Sudan, 1898 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Suez Crisis, 1951-1973
    - Ben-Gurion, David, 1973 (Box-folder 32: 5)
    - British Information Services, 1951-1957
      - 1951-1956 (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 32: 7)
    - Diplomatic correspondence and background materials, 1954-1957
      - 1954-1956 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 32: 9)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 33: 1-8)
    - Report on Sinai campaign, 1957 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Treaties and agreements concluded by the state of Israel with various countries and international organizations, 1950-1951
    - 1950 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 34: 3-4)
- Printed matter relating to the Middle East and Zionism, 1940-1984
  - Minutes of meetings and reports published by the Zionist Organization of America, 1940-1941
    - 1940 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Reports on the foreign policy of the Soviet Union published by the Hebrew University of Jerusalem
    - 1974-1977 (Box-folder 34: 7-11)
    - 1977-1984 (Box-folder 35: 1-5)
- Subject file, 1822-1952
  - Kishm, 1822-1869 (Box-folder 35: 6-7)
    - Treaties and agreements concluded by Great Britain and the United States regarding the Middle East, 1921
      - 1921-1925 (Box-folder 35: 8)
      - 1927-1930 (Box-folder 35: 9)
      - 1931-1940 (Box-folder 35: 10)
      - 1942-1948 (Box-folder 35: 11)
  - Universities in the Middle East, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 36: 1)
- Academic career file, 1974-1990
  - Correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Papers and reports by others on the Middle East, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 36: 3)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, the Middle East, and North Africa, 1928-1995
  - Bulletins, pamphlets, and serial issues, 1930-1995 (Box-folder 36: 4-5)
  - Monographs, 1936-1970 (Box-folder 36: 6-10)
  - Monographs, 1947-1956 (Box-folder 37: 1-7)
  - Monographs, 1928-1950 (Box-folder 38: 1-9)
  - Monographs, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 39: 1-4)
  - Photocopies, 1948-1985
    - Articles, 1948-1982
      - 1948-1966 (Box-folder 40: 1)
      - 1970-1982 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Monographs, 1955-1977
      - 1955-1962 (Box-folder 40: 3-10)
      - 1963-1977 (Box-folder 41: 1-9)
    - Pamphlets and reports, 1946-1985 (Box-folder 41: 10-13)
  - Reports and treaties, 1923-1937 (Box-folder 41: 14-19)
- Speeches and writings, 1951-1994
  - Documents of Near East History, 1951 (Box-folder 42: 1-4)
  - "Ottoman Diplomacy and the European State System," The Middle East Journal, 1961 Spring (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - The Middle East and North Africa in World Politics: A Documentary Record, projected volume three, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 6-9)
  - "Turkey's Relations with the United States: The Legacy of Atatürk,", 1981 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - "The Many-Sided Dispute,", 1994 (Box-folder 43: 2-12)
  - "The Many-Sided Dispute,", 1994 (Box-folder 44: 1-4)
- Subject file, 1942-1989
  - Arab propaganda, 1968 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Jerusalem, 1947-1971
    - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - 1967-1971 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - Kwitny, Joseph, 1989 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Maps, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 44: 9)
- Academic career file, 1960-1994
  - Correspondence and report from New Israel Fund, 1994 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Public Record Office log, 1988 (Box-folder 45: 2-4)
  - Translations of treaties and decrees relating to the Russian Empire, 1960 (Box-folder 45: 5-8)
    Includes correspondence (in folder 5) with O. M. Smolansky.
  - Translations of treaties and decrees relating to the Russian Empire, 1960 (Box-folder 46: 1-6)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, the Middle East, and North Africa, 1926-1984
  - Monographs, 1938-1947
    - 1938 (Box-folder 46: 7-8)
    - 1945-1947 (Box-folder 47: 1-5)
  - Pamphlets and reports, 1926-1980
    - 1926-1946 (Box-folder 47: 6-25)
    - 1946-1971 (Box-folder 48: 1-22)
    - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 49: 1-4)
  - Serial issues, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 49: 5-6)
- Speeches and writings, 1954-1993
  - "The Anglo-Egyptian Agreement on the Suez Canal Base: Political and Strategic Implications,", 1954 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - "Ottoman Diplomacy and the European State System," The Middle East Journal, 1961 Spring (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - Undergraduate Instruction on the Middle East in American Colleges and Universities, 1962 May 1 (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - "Lebanese Democracy in Its International Setting," The Middle East Journal, 1963 Autumn (Box-folder 49: 10)
  - "Undergraduate Foreign Area Studies: The Case of the Middle East," ACLS Newsletter, 1964 April (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - "The Politics of Rapid Population Growth in the Middle East," Journal of International Affairs, volume XIX, no. 1, 1965 (Box-folder 49: 12)
  - "The UN and Disimperialism in the Middle East," International Organization, volume XIX, no. 3, 1965 (Box-folder 49: 13)
  - "Military Politics in the Muslim Dynastic States, 1400-1750," Journal of the American Oriental Society, 1968 January-March (Box-folder 49: 14)
  - The Persian Gulf: Prospects for Stability, 1974 April (Box-folder 49: 15)
    Includes correspondence.
  - The Middle East and North Africa in World Politics: A Documentary Record, projected volume three, 1979 (Box-folder 49: 16-17)
  - The Middle East and North Africa in World Politics: A Documentary Record, projected volume three, 1979 (Box-folder 50: 1-7)
  - "The New Look: The Old Look in Sharper Focus," unpublished book chapter, 1980 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - Letter to the editor in reply to Edward Said, 1980 March 13 (Box-folder 50: 9)
  - Islam and World Politics: From the Rise of the European State System to Its Globalization, 1981 (Box-folder 50: 10)
    Includes correspondence and background materials.
  - Islam and World Politics: From the Rise of the European State System to Its Globalization, 1981 (Box-folder 51: 1-2)
  - "The Middle East: A Year of Turmoil," Foreign Affairs, volume 59, no. 3, 1981 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - "Egypt's Eastern Boundary: The Diplomatic Background of the 1906 Demarcation,", 1981 May 21 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - "The Interplay of Superpower and Regional Dynamics,", 1982 September 1 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Presentation to seminar on the Middle East, Harvard University, 1983 April 12 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - "Oil Nationalization in Iran, 1944-1954,", 1986 (Box-folder 51: 7)
  - "The Historical Context,", 1989 (Box-folder 51: 8)
  - "Wishful Talking," The New York Times, 1991 December 29 (Box-folder 51: 9)
  - "The Education of J. C. Hurewitz,", 1993 (Box-folder 51: 10)
- Academic career file, 1958-2001
  - Correspondence and summaries of conversations with Israeli officials, 1969-1970
    - 1969 (Box-folder 51: 11)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 51: 12)
  - Gulf 2000 list messages, 1999-2001
    - 1999 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - 2000-2001 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Reports and correspondence relating to archives in Turkey, 1958 (Box-folder 52: 3-4)
- Subject file, 1936-2001
  - Afghanistan, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 52: 5-6)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1946-1982
    Folders for 1946-1947 contain reports and correspondence relating to Palestine and the Jewish Agency.
    - 1946 (Box-folder 52: 7-8)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - Bey, Yousouf, 1966 (Box-folder 53: 4)
  - Cold War, 1926-1997 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  - Egypt, 1982-2001 (Box-folder 53: 6-7)
  - Egyptian-Israeli peace treaty, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 53: 8-9)
  - Iran, 2000 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Israel-Foreign relations, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Kuwait, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - Lebanon, 1983-1997 (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - Palestine, 1944-1991 (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - Palestine Liberation Organizations, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 54: 6)
  - Persian Gulf, 1945 (Box-folder 54: 7)
  - Persian Gulf War, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - Russian Federation and the Commonwealth of Independent States, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 54: 9)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - Soviet Union-Foreign relations-Middle East, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 11)
  - Suez settlement, 1936-1954 (Box-folder 54: 12-13)
  - Syria, 1992 (Box-folder 54: 14)
  - Turkey, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 54: 15)
  - United States-Foreign relations
    - General, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 54: 16)
    - Israel, 1979-1999
      - 1979-1995 (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - 1995-1999 (Box-folder 55: 2)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - United States. Navy, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 55: 4)
- Speeches and writings, 1949-2002
  - "Roots of Israeli Politics,", 1949 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Notes on Suez Crisis, 1954 (Box-folder 55: 6)
  - "The Superpowers and the Arab-Israeli Dispute, 1947-1973: The Politics of Mutual Denial,", 1983 (Box-folder 55: 7)
  - "The Tangled Web: The Struggle for the Mandate's Succession," unpublished manuscript, 1988-2002
    - Correspondence and notes, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 55: 8)
    - Drafts of table of contents, 1989-2002 (Box-folder 55: 9)
    - Incomplete drafts and fragments, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 55: 10-11)
    - Incomplete drafts and fragments, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 56: 1-10)
    - Incomplete drafts and fragments, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 57: 1-11)
    - Incomplete drafts and fragments, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 58: 1-12)
    - Complete drafts, 1994-2002
      - First version, 1994 (Box-folder 59: 1-9)
      - First version, 1994 (Box-folder 60: 1-5)
      - Second version, 2002 (Box-folder 60: 6-10)
      - Second version, 2002 (Box-folder 61: 1-10)
- Academic career file, 1957-2000
  - Articles and interviews, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960-2000
    - General, 1960-2000 (Box-folder 62: 2)
    - Louis, Roger, 1995 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - Course lectures on the diplomatic history of the Near and Middle East, 1957-1958
    - 1957 (Box-folder 62: 4-8)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 62: 9-10)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 63: 1-4)
  - Photostats of British Foreign Office documents relating to the Middle East, 1960 (originals dated 1799-1902) (Box-folder 63: 5-9)
  - Summaries of meetings with officials, 1972-1974
    - Egypt, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 63: 10)
    - Turkey, Israel, and Iran, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 63: 11)
- Printed matter relating to Palestine, the Middle East, and North Africa, 1876-1994
  - Bulletins and newsletters, 1944-1990 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Maps, 1918-1976
    - 1918-1944 (Box-folder 64: 2)
    - 1950-1956 (Box-folder 64: 3)
    - 1957-1959 (Box-folder 64: 4)
    - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 64: 5)
    - 1964-1976 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - Monographs, 1934-1994
    - 1934-1939 (Box-folder 64: 7-8)
    - 1942-1971 (Box-folder 65: 1-20)
    - 1975-1985 (Box-folder 66: 1-18)
    - 1988-1994 (Box-folder 67: 1-4)
  - Official correspondence, memoranda, reports, and treaties, 1876-1994
    - General, 1957-1994
      - 1957-1978 (Box-folder 67: 5)
      - 1980-1994 (Box-folder 67: 6)
    - American Universities Field Staff, 1956-1965
      - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 68: 2)
      - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 68: 3)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 68: 4)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 68: 5)
    - Great Britain, 1876-1970
      - 1876 (Box-folder 68: 6)
      - 1878 (Box-folder 68: 7)
      - 1879 (Box-folder 68: 8-9)
      - 1882 (Box-folder 68: 10-11)
      - 1883 (Box-folder 69: 1)
      - 1908-1913 (Box-folder 69: 2)
      - 1920 (Box-folder 69: 3)
      - 1921-1923 (Box-folder 69: 4)
      - 1925-1930 (Box-folder 69: 5)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 69: 6-7)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 69: 8, Map case)
      - 1940-1970 (Box-folder 69: 9)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Pamphlets, 1923-1992
    - 1923-1939 (Box-folder 70: 1)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 70: 2)
    - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 70: 3)
    - 1951-1953 (Box-folder 70: 4)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 70: 7-8)
    - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - 1965-1967 (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 71: 3-4)
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 71: 5)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 71: 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 71: 7)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 71: 8)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 72: 2)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 72: 3)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 72: 4)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 72: 5)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 72: 6)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 72: 7)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - Serial issues, 1945-1980
    - General, 1945-1980
      - 1945-1951 (Box-folder 73: 1)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 73: 2)
      - 1965-1980 (Box-folder 73: 3)
    - Articles et documents, 1950-1953
      - 1950 (Box-folder 73: 4-5)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 73: 6)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 73: 7-8)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - International Conciliation, 1949-1952
      - 1949 (Box-folder 74: 2)
      - 1950-1952 (Box-folder 74: 3)
    - Notes et études documentaires, 1946-1952
      - 1946-1949 (Box-folder 74: 4)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 74: 5)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 74: 6)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 74: 7)
    - Problèmes économiques, 1949-1952
      - 1949 (Box-folder 74: 8)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 74: 9)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 74: 10)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 74: 11)
- Subject file, 1920-1981
  - Afghanistan, 1951 (Box-folder 74: 12)
  - Algeria, 1957-1981
    - 1957 (Box-folder 75: 1-2)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 75: 3)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 75: 4)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 75: 5-6)
  - Arab World, 1952-1967 (Box-folder 75: 7)
  - Egypt, 1950 (Box-folder 75: 8)
  - Egyptian-Israeli Peace Treaty, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - Government cabinet ministers in the Middle East, 1965 (Box-folder 75: 10-11)
  - Iraq and Syria, 1963 (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - Jerusalem, 1982 (Box-folder 76: 2)
  - Jewish refugees, 1943 (Box-folder 76: 3)
  - Kuwait, 1961 (Box-folder 76: 4)
  - League of Nations, 1925-1941 (Box-folder 76: 5)
  - Mesopotamia, 1920 (Box-folder 76: 6)
  - Military politics, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 76: 7)
  - Nasser, Gamal Abdul, 1966 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), 1967-1974 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - Palestine (British mandate), 1938-1948
    - General, 1943-1948
      - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 77: 1)
      - 1944 (Box-folder 77: 2-3)
      - 1945 (Box-folder 77: 4)
      - 1946-1948 (Box-folder 77: 5)
    - Amīn al-Husainī, Grand Mufti, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 77: 6)
    - Arab armies, 1939-1947 (Box-folder 77: 7)
    - Arab propaganda, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 77: 8)
    - Economy, 1938-1947 (Box-folder 78: 1)
    - Education, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 78: 2)
    - Great Britain, 1938-1947
      - General, 1938-1947 (Box-folder 78: 3)
      - Relations with Jews, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 78: 4)
    - Haganah, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 78: 5)
    - Illegal arms, 1943-1947
      - 1943 (Box-folder 78: 6)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 78: 7)
      - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 78: 8)
    - Immigration, 1944-1947
      - 1944-1946 (Box-folder 78: 9)
      - 1946-1947 (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Irgun Zevai Leumi, 1944-1947
      - 1944 (Box-folder 79: 2)
        Includes report on the Stern Group.
      - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 79: 3)
    - Jewish refugees, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 79: 4)
    - Labor unions, 1943-1947
      - General, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 79: 5)
      - Histradut, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 79: 6)
    - Local government, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 79: 7)
    - Police, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 79: 8)